Thinh Nguyen

Kemp, TX

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Thinh-Nguyen/3db1adf3e08f35ec

Senior RF Test Engineer /RF Electronic Technician with experience in all aspects of the RF Electronic field including: RF filters, High speed cable, RF audio/video/camera radio systems and wireless networking transmitter and receiver systems.

Strong experience in integrating, testing and troubleshooting RF related products; RF circuit diagnostics including solid expertise manually testing and troubleshooting audio and/or video products (transmitters, receivers, amplifiers and antennas) from system to component level; configuration wireless networking Tx/ Rx surveillance systems; and reading schematics and drawings.

Work Experience

Sr. RF Technician.

BAE SYSTEMS - Dallas, TX January 2020 to Present

- Test, troubleshoot and configure RF products (transmitters, receivers, antennas and amplifiers) from system to component level.
- Use multiple RF test equipment such as: Marconi Radio communications, Gain & noise figure measurement.

Signal Generation, modulation and demodulation, Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer, Power meter and most of other daily use RF test equipment.

Owner - Self Employed.

T&N Poultry Farm (Sanderson Poultry farm contractor) - Malakoff, TX May 2016 to January 2020

• Managing 8 enclosed barns, using the Rotem Control system to automatic administer large operation of the farm.

Sr. LAB TEST TECHNICIAN

TE CONNECTIVITY - MADISON CABLE - Worcester, MA February 2012 to May 2016

- Perform electrical and physical test on high frequency (Up to 40GHz) cooper and silver platted cables such as parallel, twisted and multiple pair (up to 32 pair).
- Work with New Developing Team on new high speed and high-performance data transmitting cable.
- Responsible for calibrating and setting up test parameters on 4 Ports Network Analyzer, DSA8200, CSA8200,

TDS8000.

Sr. RF PRODUCTION TEST TECHNICIAN

COBHAM TACTICAL COMMUNICATIONS AND SURVEILLANCE - Nashua, NH October 2008 to February 2012

● Test, troubleshoot and configure RF products include wireless Audio and Video (transmitters, receivers, antennas and amplifiers) from system to component level.

• Configure, test and troubleshoot camera wireless networking surveillance systems.

Sr. CENTRAL RECEIVE ANTENNA INTEGRATE AND TEST TECHNICIAN

MICROWAVE RADIO COMMUNICATIONS - Billerica, MA September 2005 to October 2008

- Systems integrate, configure, test and troubleshoot steerable microwave Central Receive Antennas and controller systems for TV broadcast industry. Master Controller GUI configuration includes software manipulation in a Visual Basic environment to set control parameters.
- \bullet Responsible for testing and troubleshoot analog and digital modules of Tx and Rx.

Thinh Nguyen 1

RF Product Engineer

MICRO NETWORKS - Worcester, MA September 2000 to August 2002

- Improvement testing of new product (CDR, VCO, SAW filters, Wafer) development process.
- Transferring new product from R&D department to production.
- Generate test procedures. Modify product design and performance to meet product expectations.

RF Technician

TRAK MICROWAVE - Tampa, FL July 1999 to August 2000

- Directly involved with closing and transferring RF products from Daden Anthony Associates facility in California to Trak Microwave in Tampa, Florida.
- Prototyping, testing, troubleshooting and alignment of switch filters, GPS LNA/Filter assemblies and MIC (micro integrated circuit) products.
- Experience in high frequency products range from DC to 40GHz.

RF Technician

DADEN ANTHONY ASSOCIATES, INC. - San Clemente, CA September 1997 to July 1999

• Directly responsible for alignment and testing of complex IF, RF and microwave filters – covering the frequency range from DC to 40GHz.

RF Test Engineer

FSY MICROWAVE, INC. - Columbia, MD September 1994 to September 1997

• Responsible for prototyping lumped element band-pass, low-pass, high-pass, band-pass reject, diplexers, triplexes and cavity filters.

Education

LICENSE in TEXAS REAL ESTATE SALES AGENT

IPC

2021

GENERAL INDUSTRY COURSE

TRINITY VALLEY COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Mechanical Engineering Technology

QUINSIGAMOND COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Worcester, MA 2018

Electronic and Computer Engineering Technology

HILLSBOROUGH COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Tampa, FL 1999 to 2000

WORCESTER POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE - Worcester, MA 2000

Science Management Information Systems

PRINCE GEORGE'S COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Largo, MD 1994 to 1998

Certifications and Licenses

o IPC

Α

610 certified o Advanced Network & Security Certified (2008) o OSHA 10-HOURS GENERAL INDUSTRY COURSE (2018) TRINITY VALLEY COMMUNITY COLLEGE (In progress)

Mechanical Engineering Technology/Solidworks & HASS CNC programing 2018 QUINSIGAMOND COMMUNITY COLLEGE, Worcester, MA.

Electromechanical, AS Degree, Average GPA 3.5 2013

Electronics Technology Certificate, Average GPA 3.75 2009 WORCESTER POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE (WPI), Worcester, Massachusetts 2000

WPI's Six Sigma Process & Quality Improvements Certified (Black belt) HILLSBOROUGH COMMUNITY COLLEGE, Tampa, Florida. 1999

2000

Major: Electronic and Computer Engineering Technology, Average GPA 3.6 PRINCE GEORGE'S COMMUNITY COLLEGE. Largo, Maryland 1994

1998

Major: Studies in Science Management Information Systems, Average GPA 3.0 Thinh Nguyen 2